Resume

Atul Tripathi

A- 47 Sect or 12 vijay Nagar Ghaziabad

Phone: 8750104313, 8010173214 Email: atultripathi571@gmail.com

Summary:

Highly motivated, detailed oriented, quick learner and energetic Financial Accountant 5 years of experience in the finance domain, with excellent deadline driven, analytical and strong organizational skills Excellent communication skills with a talent f or analyzing problems, developing and simplifying procedures, and finding innovative solutions for job efficiency Strong customer service skills, flexible, dependable, and work very well with others as well as independently.

Career Objective

Seeking assignment in the domain of Finance domain in a reputed organization that provides an inspiring work environment with an opportunity to utilize and enhance my intellectual capability.

Finance Skills:

- Prepared Financial Statements of Companies, Partnership Firm, Proprietorship Firm
- Prepared Income tax returns of Individuals
- Filling of all Statutory Returns such as TDS Returns, GST Returns
- Done Internal Audit of Companies
- Process Journal entries and perform corrections to ensure accurate data
- Analyze, Examined and Interpreted records, Compiled Financial Information and reconciled reports and Financial data
- Handling all the Taxation matter of the Company such as Filling of TDS Returns and Income Tax Returns and ESIC, PF
- Preparing Financial Statements of the company on monthly basis

- Debtor & Creditor Reconciliation
- Monthly Management Information system data Prepare
- Handling Income Tax scrutiny
- Financial statement Prepare and project ion statement Prepare.
- Revenue Leakage
- Salary Reconciliation and Salary Process
- Budgeting Forecasting and Financial Planning

Professional Experience:

As Sr. Accountant in Nationwide Immigration Service Pvt Ltd From Oct 20 to Till Date

Responsibility:

- Filling of all Statutory Returns such as TDS Returns like 24Q and 26Q, GST Returns like GSTR3B,GSTR1 and Annual GST Return
- Handling Income Tax scrutiny
- Preparing Management Information System
- Day to Day Accounting like reconciliations
- Forecasting and Budgeting

As Finance Executive in Data Resolve Technologies Pvt Ltd from June'18 to Apr'20

Responsibility:

- Managing company accounts, supervising daily accounting activity.
- Maintaining Tax compliances GST, TDS, PF, ESI and all other statutory obligations in company as per govt rules.
- Responsible for Direct and Indirect Tax, Capital Expenditure & maintenance.
- Taxation: GST, TDS, Income Tax, monthly returns, Assessment etc Preparation and Filing of Income Tax Returns, T.D.S. Returns, GST Return.
- Preparation of Annual Returns and all other company relating documents filed with the Registrar of Companies.
- Bank Reconciliation.
- TDS Data Prepare & timely deduction & deposit, submission of returns &

issuance of TDS certificates

- .
- Preparation of GST Returns Data & filling Gstr-1, Gstr-3B & GST Annual Return, GST Refund.
- Debtors and Creditors Account Reconciliation.
- Maintain the Sales Tax Forms & Issued timely to party.
- Maintain Payroll & PF ESIC.
- Preparation of P & L Account and Balance Sheet.

As Accountant in ASL infosystems Pvt Ltd from Mar 2017 to May 2018

- Day to Day Accounting
- Vendors Payment
- Filling of all Statutory Returns such as TDS Returns like 24Q and 26Q, GST Returns like GSTR3B, GSTR1 and Annual GST Return
- Salary Process and reconciliation
- PF & ESIC payment
- Bank reconciliation

As Junior Accountant in Eternal HR Service Pvt Ltd from theperiod Aug2016 to Dec 2016

- Cash Handling and Reconciliation ion
- Salary Reconciliation and Salary Process
- Reimbursement process
- Day To Day Accounting

As External Auditor in State bank of India from the period June 2015 to July 2016

- Financial statement Prepare And project ion statement Prepare.
- Revenue Leakage
- Loan Document Prepared.

Educational Qualification:

- Master of Business Administration (Core Finance) 2018-2020 (Subharti University)
- Bachelor of commerce 2012-2016 (university of Delhi)
- Secondary school 2011-2012(CBSE)
- High School 2009- 2010 (CBSE)

Personal Detail:

• Father Name: Vidya Vishal Tripathi

Date of Birth :01 Dec 1994Marital Status: Unmarried

Declaration: I hereby Declared that above Information is true and correct to the best of My knowledge.

(Atul Tripathi)